《老爸们》在摄影棚现场录制
Dads is recorded in front of a live studio audience.
Edna...
你知道我的收据在哪么?
Do you know, uh, where my receipts are?
- 啥?  - 收据
- Que?  - Receipts.
就是你在店里买了东西之后拿到的那个小纸票?
The little slips of paper you get when you buy things in a store?
啥?
Que?
收据
Receipts.
就是  你纳税的时候需要用到的那个东西
You know, you need 'em for when you file your taxes.
- 税呀...  - 对
- Taxes...  - Yeah.
您真逗  Eli先生
You funny, Mr. Eli.
纳税...
Taxes...
老爸  你刚才在那里面干嘛?
Dad, what were you doing in there?
短道速滑
Short-track speed-skating.
你以为我能干嘛?
What do you think I was doing?
嘿...  你从哪找到的?
Hey...  Where did you get that?
从楼上那几个箱子里拿的
From one of those boxes upstairs.
别担心  你有一大堆这些玩意
Don't worry, you got tons of these.
不  不  不  不  不  不行
No, no, no, no, no, no.
这可是自由联盟第21期
This is Freedom League number 21.
噢?  是么?
Ooh, it is?
这是关于黄金时代自由联盟和来自Beta星球的白银时代自由联盟
Yes. This is the first team-up between the Golden Age Freedom League
第一次结盟的记录
and the Silver Age Freedom Society of Earth Beta.
你知不知道这到底多有价值?
Do you have any idea how much this is worth?
换来四年高中处男之身
Four years of high school virginity.
老爸  你不能把我的漫画书带进厕所  明白?
Dad, you cannot bring my comic books into the bathroom, okay?
它们对我来说很重要
They mean a lot to me.
比我还重要?
More than I mean to you?
听着  重点是  如果你要继续住下去
Look, the point is, if you're going to live here,
你得尊重我的习惯
you have to respect my things.
不过  你也得尊重我的习惯  伙计
Well, you've got to respect my things, buddy.
伙计?
Buddy?
我一下忘了你的名字
I blanked on your name for a minute.
不好意思  老大
Sorry, Chief.
老爸们  第一季  第八集
天天美剧字幕组 www.ttmeiju.com
本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
翻译: 水果虫虫  Luca  佛剑分说  LadyMiao
校对: 兰陵笑笑生
呃  Warner  这有些销账我看得不太明白
Um, Warner, I'm not sure about some of these write-offs.
这个600美元的西服收据是怎么回事?
Uh, what's this receipt for a $600 suit?
这个  额  是为了跟一个有投资意向的客户进行商务会议买的
That was, uh, a business meeting with a potential investor.
他投资了么?
Did he invest?
没有  不过  呃...
No, but he, uh...
他有赞我西服好看
he said "nice suit."
好吧  为什么你的西服会那么贵?
Well, why would a suit for you cost that much?
你的身材就跟《价格猜猜看》里那个麦克风一样
You have the body of a PRICE IS RIGHT microphone.
我没那么瘦
I'm not that skinny.
噢  够啦  儿子
Oh, come on, son.
你瘦的你娘在生你的时候都没意识到自己在分娩
You were so skinny your mother didn't know she was in labor.
她就那么从沙发上下来然后发现你都出生了
She just got up off the couch and there you were.
感谢上帝让我们有塑料沙发套
Thank God for plastic slipcovers.
嗨  不好意思我来晚啦同志们
Hey. Sorry I'm late, guys
我刚才不得不把我所有的漫画搬出公寓
I had to get all my comics out of my apartment
弄到一个储藏间里去
and put 'em in a storage unit.
你为什么那么做?
Why would you do that?
我看到我老爸从厕所里出来
I caught my dad coming out of the bathroom
手里拿着自由联盟21期
reading Freedom League 21.
等等  那个是他们第一次的交集  白银时代自由联盟
Wait, that's the first crossover between the Silver Age Freedom League
- 和黄金时代自由联盟  - 和黄金时代自由联盟  对
- and the Golden Age Freedom Society...  - Golden Age Freedom Society, yeah.
- 你得把那些书救出去  - 当然
- You had to get them out of there.  - Of course.
你们可知道校霸人物肯定爱死在这工作了
You know who'd love working here is a schoolyard bully.
- 我爱这些漫画书  - 我也是
- I love those comics.  - Yeah.
要是我能拿到那个系列我能对它们做些什么...
What I would do to that collection if I got my hands on it...
嘿  嘿  别冲动呀
Hey, hey, easy.
头一个小时  我要把它展开  然后像个变态一样盯着它看
The first hour, I'd spread it out and just stare at it like a psychopath.
然后我开始细细品读它  慢慢品读它
And then I'd slowly start reading it and reading it,
接着逐渐加快速度
and I'd read it harder...
从前玩味到后  从后玩味到前  顶在墙上继续
front to back, back to front, up against a wall.
不可能  你最多就读个两分钟
No way. You'd-you'd read it in two minutes,
然后就一声抱歉倒头睡着
apologize, and just fall asleep.
你说的对
You're right.
他以前经常在他妈和我还正在看考斯比一家的时候
He used to fall asleep on the couch with his comics
就在沙发上抱着漫画睡着了
while his mother and I watched The Cosby Show.
你和你老婆经常一起看电视?
You and your wife watch a lot of TV together?
是呀  演到Huxtables把Rudy的金鱼丢进马桶冲掉的时候
Yeah, she told me she was leaving me
她告诉我她要离开我了
while the Huxtables flushed Rudy's goldfish down the toilet.
嘿  Warner  你也收集漫画书?
Hey, Warner,you had a comic book collection, too?
是呀  我有过  有过大量藏书
Yeah, I had... I had quite the collection.
我以前有3752册
I had 3,752.
你的藏书怎么了?
What happened to it?
- 我老爸给我卖掉了  - 不对  我是拿去交换了
- My dad sold it.  - No, I swapped them.
你记不记得那些给我们一堆毯子的印第安人?
Remember, those Indians gave us all those blankets?
然后我们病的很重那次?
We got so sick?
我有去过那个集市想要撤销本次交易
I tried to go back to the trading post to reverse the deal,
结果只剩一个空空的停车场了
and it was nothing but an empty parking lot
没有人知道我说的集市在哪里
and nobody had any idea what I was talking about.
当然 在那个时候
Of course, at that point,
我经常都在喝酒吸粉儿就是了
I was living on Reggie bars and angel dust.
孩子们都睡了
The kids are asleep.
谢谢 宝贝
Oh, thanks, honey.
你穿的是什么
What are you wearing?
哦 我只是想穿得
Oh, I thought I'd just slip into
舒服一点
something a little more comfortable.
那是我的裤子
Those are my pants.
看看标签
Read the label.
Abigail Landress[款式名]
拉链在屁股上 亲
The zipper's on the hip, there, buddy.
007 也这么穿
Just like 007.
好吧 要不咱们还是把
Okay, well, why don't you just
你的牛仔裤从衣服堆里翻出来
take your jeans out of the laundry basket
然后我们就算翻篇儿了
and we'll never speak of this again.
好吧
Yep.
喔
Whoa.
Camila 来给我介绍下你的朋友
Camila, introduce me to your friend.
Oh...
对不起拉 孩子
Hi, son. I'm sorry.
我只是特别喜欢穿 landress 的屁股
I'm-I'm just a sucker for a Landress backside.
来 这些是给你的
Here, these are for you.
是什么东西
What do you got there?
来 过来看一眼
Well, take a look.
哇 老爸 太牛了
Oh, my God, Dad,
满满的都是漫画书啊
these are filled with comics. Mm-hmm.
看这个
Look at this.
X战警
X-Men...
嗯
Yep.
超人
Superman...
上面白白的奶酪
The head cheese.
蝙蝠侠与罗宾
Batman and Robin...
一上一下[这两句都有很黄的意思]
Top and bottom.
好吧 你现在这么说就只是把里面很爽的东西吸出来罢了
Okay, now you're starting to suck all the fun out of it.
没 这事儿一般都是罗宾干的
Oh, that's a job for Robin.
我只是很抱歉之前把你的漫画拿去和
Yeah, I just felt so bad that I swapped your comics
那些可能是鬼的人换了
with those people who might be ghosts, and, uh...
所以我决定给你搞点新的来
I decided to get you some new ones.
老爸
Dad...
太好了 谢谢你
this is amazing! Thank you.
这些你从哪儿搞来的
Wh-Where did you get these?
我电脑来的
I computered 'em.
我发现有个城叫58
Turns out there is this guy named Craig
城里面的市场
who has this list of all sorts of stuff
什么东西都有卖
that he sells.
不管是漫画啦
From comics to...
老的家具啦 汽车啦
to old furniture, to cars... Yeah.
而且我觉得那个城 搞不好是个红灯区
And I think he may be some kind of pimp.
4000美元的家用报警系统
$4,000 for a home security system?
多划算啊
That's totally a write-off.
我家里可有不少公司的贵重财产
I have all kinds of valuable company assets at home.
比如说
Like what?
我
Like me.
自从他看了 《绑架》之后
Yeah, ever since he saw Taken,
他就一直很怕被藏在床底下的人
he's been worried someone's gonna
给拖出去
drag him out from under his bed
然后把他卖了当性奴
and sell him into sexual slavery.
自从我看了《绑架2》
Ever since I saw Taken 2,
我就觉得这事儿还会再次发生
I've been worried that it was gonna happen again.
所以说 你爱你的漫画么
So, are you loving your comics?
喔 他们太爽了
Oh, my God, they're so good.
嗯
Yeah.
我等不及要给你炫耀
I mean, I can't wait to show you.
他跟你的一样好
I-I... they're as good as yours.
等等
Okay, come on.
我是说
I mean...
等等 亲
slow down there, Tex.
什么
What?
你爸爸从
Your dad buys
网上买的便宜漫画
some cheapo collection off the Internet
比得过我的多年珍藏
and it's as good as mine?
怎么可能
Come on.
你还真好意思说啊 同志
That is some pretty bold talk, there, fella.
我可不是只是说说 仁兄
Oh, it's not just talk, partner.
哦 真的么
Oh! Oh, is that right?
好吧 那既然这样
Well, I'll tell you what...
你给我看你的 我就给你看我的
you show me yours, I'll show you mine.
嗯 当年你们在洗澡肥皂掉了的时候
Wow, this is what it must've been like
肯定也是这么说的吧
in the Old Gay West.
所以我把所有七十年代的X战警漫画
So we get all my X-Men from the '70s,
还有所有神奇四侠的漫画
and I'll get all my Fantastic Fours...
我很害怕储存单元
Ugh, storage units creep me out.
为什么
Why?
我在四岁之前全家都住在储存单元里面
Our whole family lived in one till I was four.
嗯 你们开心就好
Well, as long as you were happy.
一点都不开心
I wasn't.
幸好我不是移民
Gosh, I'm so glad I don't come from other places.
我的漫画没了
My comics are gone!
淡定
Quiet down!
小声点儿 有人还要睡觉呢
Yeah! People trying to sleep!
所以
Now...
除了你的小人儿书之外
...were you storing anything else
你还放了其他东西没有
besides your cartoons?
额 那叫漫画书
Uh, they're comic books.
我怎么说的来着
What did I say?
你说的小人儿书
Oh, you called them cartoons.
我的神啊
God!
完了 我肯定会因为这种严肃的原因被炒鱿鱼的
I hope they don't take my badge away for that.
你呢 女士
How about you, miss?
你是不是他的...
Are you his...
当然不是
No.
万幸 万幸
Good for you.
所以说 除了你的小人书
Now, aside from your cartoons,
你说你还丢了几个星际迷航的激光
you say you're missing several Star Trek lasers?
是相位器
Uh... phasers.
有什么区别么
What's the difference?
嗯 激光是集中的光束
Well, a laser is a focused beam of light,
相位器是导向性能量武器
whereas a phaser is a directed-energy weapon.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
那么你是想
Well, are you gonna
派个法医小组
get a forensics team down here
来这采集指纹和DNA样本么
and fingerprint everything and then get some DNA samples?
当然
Oh, sure.
《识骨寻踪》里的女士们正在来的路上呢
The Bones lady is on her way over.
听起来像是在挖苦我
It sounds like you're being sarcastic.
绝对没有
Not at all.
哦 很好
Well, great. Good.
那多久才能抓到这些罪犯
How... so how long until you track down these criminals?
一旦我们收到天空中蝙蝠侠的信号
Well, once we get the Bat-Signal in the sky,
进展就会很快
things move along pretty quickly.
这
See, that...
听起来又是在挖苦我
sounds like you're being sarcastic again.
并没有哦
But it's not.
这全都是
This is all
你的错
your fault!
是在说我么还是
Is it me or does he say that
他每次进门都这么吼
every time he walks in here?
我跟你不熟
Don't talk to me like we friends.
哥所有的漫画书都没了
All of my comics are gone!
全部都没了
All of them are gone!
为了防着你我才把他们放到储藏室的
Stolen from the storage unit that I had to put them in
结果都被偷了
to keep them from you!
就像我常说的
Well, like I always say,
永远别把东西放到任何地方
never put anything anywhere.
爸 这些漫画书
Dad, those comics were
是我保存自童年的一份美好回忆
the one happy memory I had from childhood.
但是你非要搬到这里
But you had to move in here
并确保了那份美好回忆也被破坏
and make sure that even that was ruined, too.
问问伊丽莎白斯玛特她的童年如何[被囚禁十年]
Ask Elizabeth Smart about her childhood.
看看她怎么说
See what she says.
孩子
Mijo...
这个给你玩
I bring for you...
因为你把你的米老鼠漫画弄丢了
because you lose your Mickey Mice books.
这是我们墨西哥的游戏机
Is Xbox of Mexico.
- 他的书全都没了?  - 嗯
- So they were just gone? - Mm-hmm.
- 天 Eli肯定要疯了  - 是啊
- God, Eli must be crushed. - Yeah.
他哭了
He cried.
真的?
He did?
真的
Yeah.
前两分钟看着还蛮可爱的
The first two minutes were kind of cute,
然后就开始冒鼻涕泡
Then he got that snot bubble thing...
哦天啊 Eli
Oh, my God, Eli.
我简直不敢相信
I-I can't believe it.
你怎么样了
How are you dealing?
过一天是一天吧
I'm day to day.
直到犯罪事件发生到自己身上
You know, I never really cared about crime
我才开始关注它
until it happened to me.
好吧 你可以随时来看我的漫画
Well, you-you know, you're welcome to read my comics
直到警察找回你的
until they find yours.
- 真的么  - 真的
- Really? - Yeah.
- 当然 来吧  - 好吧
Yeah, come on. Okay.
还真不少啊
Wow, you got a lot.
是啊 挺大一盒的
Yeah. That's a big box.
- 这本看起来不错  - 是啊
- Oh. This is pretty good. - Yeah.
我也有这本的
Oh, I had this one.
还有这本
And this one.
And this one...
还有这本
and this one...
and this one.
Warner
我觉得这些可能是我的漫画
I think these might be my comics.
等等 等等
Wait, wait.
你觉得是我爸偷偷溜进你的储藏室偷了你的漫画
My dad snuck into your storage space and stole your comics?
我没
I don't...
要是没有别人的帮助
He can't even get through a revolving door
他甚至连旋转门都过不去
without help from somebody.
- 老爸  - 什么
- Dad... - Yeah?
你从网上谁那
...what was the name of the guy
买的这些漫画
you bought these from online?
是那个口水香肠九号阿特吧唧嘴点儿嘎呜
Oh, that was SlobberSausageNine@lipsmacking.gov
这些书就放在他的后备箱里
Yeah, he had those in his trunk,
旁边放着整箱的香烟和运动鞋
along with cartons of cigarettes and sneakers.
实际上 这也是他卖给我的
In fact, he sold me these.
阿迪逗斯
Adidos.
这些可能真是你的
Maybe they do belong to you.
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧
Okay,
如果你百分之百确定这些都是你的
if you are 100% sure that these are yours...
我不能留着 我是说 它们
I-I can't take them. I mean, they're...
好吧 我也没那么确定啦
Well, I mean, I'm not 100%.
盒子换了 顺序也不一样 所以
They're in a different box and they're out of order, so...
我还是不能要
Well, I can't take them
如果你比较确定的话 所以
if you're pretty sure they're yours, so...
额
Oh, well...
我不是
I'm not...
别 别 别 你别这样
No, no, no, you don't.
这又是一出珍娜莱西事件
This is Jenna Lacy all over again.
珍娜莱西 这跟她有什么关系
Jenna Lacy? What does she have to do with this?
你不记得了么 我本想约她出去
Oh, you don't remember? Well, I wanted to ask her out,
但我觉得可能你也喜欢她
but I thought that you might like her,
所以我问你 兄弟
and so I said, "Hey, dude, are you
你要约她么
gonna ask her out?"
然后你表示 不 我一点都不喜欢她
And you were like, "No, I don't even like her."
然后我约了她
And so I asked her out,
结果你的确喜欢她
and it turned out you did like her,
然后你就表示 嘿 我喜欢她
and then you were all, like, "Hey, I liked her.
你为什么要约她
Why you asking her out?"
好吧 我不要了 给你吧
Okay, I'm not gonna take'em. Just take'em.
不 不 我不要
No, no, I'm not gonna take'em.
不 我不会要的
No, I'm not gonna take'em.
Warner 我们是25年的老朋友了
Look, Warner, we've been friends for 25 years.
- 我希望你留着  - 不 我不能要
- I want you to have them. - No, I can't do that.
拿着啊 拿着啊
Take these. Take these.
但愿你们没有这样对待珍娜莱西的盒子[双关]
I hope you didn't handle Jenna Lacy's box that way.
如果这样你能开心 那我拿走好
I'll take 'em. If it'll make you happy, I'll take'em.
我有一条那样的裤子
I have those pants.
我简直不能相信他竟然把它们搬走了
I can't believe he took them.
他可是说了要送给你的
Well, he did offer them to you.
我常说
Like I always say,
给什么要什么
always take everything.
是啊  至少
Yeah, well, at least
我没在你身上学到
I didn't learn the difference
如何区分是非对错
between right and wrong from you.
哦  是么?  那是谁让你学会的  超人?
Oh, yeah? Who'd you learn it from, Superman?
是啊  还有蝙蝠侠
Yes. And Batman.
还有神奇女侠
And Wonder Woman.
还有潜水侠教过我游泳
And Aquaman taught me how to swim,
所以我到现在还不会游
which is why I cannot swim.
你不会游泳?
You can't swim?
孩子  你妈妈在这方面还真是失误啊
Boy, your mother really dropped the ball on that one.
她之所以那么辛苦工作就是因为你不顾家!
Well, she was busy working because you weren't around!
天哪  至少曾经我还有漫画书
God! At least my comic books were there for me!
至少我会游泳!
At least I could swim!
怎么了?
What?
好吧  我不是个好父亲
Okay, I'm a bad father
所以他就得用漫画书
And so he had to fill the void
来填补缺失的父爱么?
I left in his life with comic books?
那我应该怎么做?
What am I supposed to do about it?
去Warner家把它们偷回来?
Go to Warner's and steal them back?
要是你能安静上五秒钟
Well, if you'd shut up for five seconds,
咱们就可以出发了
we could get out of here.
哦  伙计
Oh, boy,
Warner家的安保系统可是很牛的
Warner's got some fancy security system.
不要紧  我有密码
It's okay, I have password.
月黑风高杀人夜
Is a good night to die.
Edna  我们只是去拿漫画书
Edna, we're just getting the comic books.
一切尽在掌握
We see how it goes.
喂
Psst!
你干什么呢!?
What are you doing?!
抱歉  习惯了!
Sorry. Habit!
Edna  咱们上楼去
Edna, let's go upstairs.
好了  到手了  咱们撤
All right, we got 'em. Let's go.
他那还有一本呢
He has more.
好吧  好吧
All right, all right.
啊!
Uh!
你的手法不对!  笨蛋  闪开!
You do it wrong! Estúpido, move!
快动手
Andale!
妈妈...
Mama...
晚安啦  孩子
Buenas noches, niño.
Crawford?
有人在下面么?
Anyone down here?
哦  爽了
Whew! Got it.
好吧  给我按顺序从头到尾讲
Okay, so walk me through the sequence of events again.
好的  我听到有声音
Okay, I heard a noise,
发现自己的漫画书不见了  就跑下楼
I noticed my comics were gone, I ran downstairs.
这里闻上去真是太糟了
It smelled really bad right here.
我跑出去然后发现
I ran outside and noticed
安保系统的电线被切断了
that the security system's wires were cut.
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey.  - Hey.
- 我收到了你的信息  - 是啊
- I got your message.  - Yeah.
等一下  我认识你
Wait a minute. I know you.
昨天我刚把你的案子文件扔掉了
I threw your file away yesterday.
简直难以置信  竟然有人闯入偷走我的漫画书
I can't believe somebody broke in here and stole my comics.
好吧  我不想搞得这么尴尬
Well, okay, I don't-I don't mean to be awkward,
但...  但是你把它们给我了啊  是我的漫画书了
but-but you gave 'em to me. They're-They're my comics.
我的意思是  你拿走吧  没错
Well, I mean, you took them, yes,
但我觉得咱俩都认可  这些漫画还是属于我的
but I think we both know that they are still mine.
等一下
Wait a minute.
我觉得我开始明白了
I think I'm starting to figure this out.
我丢失的东西只有这些漫画书
My comics were the only thing that were missing, and you
而你是唯一知道它们放在这里的人
are the only person that knew they were here.
你偷了我的漫画  是你偷了我的漫画!
You stole my comics. You stole my comics!
小偷!
Thief!
逮捕他!
Arrest him!
不  你才是购买赃物的人
No, you are the one that purchased stolen goods.
所以应该逮捕他!
So arrest him!
我不知道  他先说的
I don't know. He asked first.
我经常是这么判断应该抓谁的
That's usually how I decide who to arrest.
我打赌要是咱们现在就去你的公寓
I bet if we go over to your apartment right now,
肯定会发现漫画就在你家
you'll see the comics right there.
- 哦  你这么肯定?  - 当然
- Oh, you do?  - Yeah.
怎么样啊?  是啊  是啊
How about that? Yeah, yeah.
- 哦  真是太棒了  - 欢迎来家
- Oh, that's great.  - Be my guest.
- 行啊!  - 这就走
- Okay. Aa!  - Here we go.
呃
Uh...!
你知道  呃...
You know, uh...
那个Morgan Freeman真是碉堡了  不是么?
that Morgan Freeman is really terrific, isn't he?
向天发誓  我真不知道这些怎么跑到这里来的
I swear to God, I have no idea how these got here.
等等  等一下
Wait, wait, wait.
他...  他并没有偷这些东西
He-He-He didn't steal this nonsense.
是我们干的
We did.
什么?
What?
你们俩要自我申辩一下么?
You two care to explain yourselves?
她放的屁!
She farted!
亲爱的  那个...  那个是你干的么?
Honey, that-that was you on the landing?
我只是  我以前从来没有当着你的面放过屁
I, just, I never farted in front of you before
因为我希望自己在你心目中始终保持完美
because I just wanted you to keep thinking I was perfect.
结束了
Well, that's over.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我...  我从来没有意识到你为我做了这么多牺牲
I, I never realized how much you sacrifice for me.
别太使劲挤她
Don't squeeze her too hard.
现在臭屁之谜已经解开
Now that the Farty Boys have solved the case
已经知道是谁放的了
of the mysterious smell,
现在咱们可以回到正题了吧?
can we get back to the matter at hand?
这些到底是谁的漫画?
Whose comics are these?
好吧  是他的
All right, they're his.
是我们俩的
They're ours.
真的?
Really?
是的  没错
Yeah. Yeah.
警官  我不会起诉的
Officer, I'm not gonna press charges.
那可不是你说了算的
That was never an option for you.
老爸  你替我把书偷回来
Dad, you stole these for me.
我真不知道该说什么好
I don't know what to say.
我知道
I do.
我以前真的没意识到这些穿着紧身衣的2货
I didn't realize these ridiculous men in tights
对于你来说这么重要
meant so much to you.
现在我明白为什么你看着他们
I can see now why you looked to them
去获得某种精神支持
for some kind of support.
而我现在就在这  也许你的想法会有所改变
So now that I'm here, maybe you'll think differently.
我很抱歉  儿子
I'm sorry, son.
呃
Uh,
好像我是第一次听到你这么叫我"儿子"
it's, like, the first time I've heard you call me "son".
你又把我的名字忘了  是不是?
You blanked on my name again, didn't you?
行了  咱们离开这里吧
Come on. Let's get out of here.
女士  站在那里
Ma'am, stop right there.
我要走在你前面
I'm gonna walk ahead of you.
欢迎加入天天美剧字幕组
@天天美剧
www.ttmeiju.com